A Guide to the Papers of Francis Perry Dunnington, 1867-1928
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Francis Perry Dunnington 1867-1928
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
1888
This collection consists of ca. 30 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This material was received as a gift by the Library from the estate of Francis Perry Dunnington, on March 16, 1944.
Scope and Content Information
Francis Perry Dunnington (1851-1944), a University of Virginia graduate from Baltimore, Maryland, attended the University from 1867-1868 and 1870-1872. He graduated in June of 1872 with degrees in applied mathematics and moral philosophy and a degree as a civil and mining engineer. In the fall of 1872, he joined the faculty of the University as Adjunct Professor of Analytical and Agricultural Chemistry; he was made a full professor of the School of Analytical and Agricultural Chemistry in 1885. The Department of Pharmacy was established in the fall of 1886, and Dunnington also lectured in this department. In 1894 when the faculty of the University were presented with the idea of admitting women to the University, Dunnington was among the minority of those faculty who supported the move. He retired in 1919 as Professor of Analytical and Industrial Chemistry and is noted in the 1919-1920 catalog as being "on the Carnegie Foundation."
The majority of this collection is related to the University and Dunnington's activities as a chemistry instructor. There is a math notebook from his student days, as well as a volume containing notes on his lectures for "Industrial Chemistry." There is also material, 1878-1889, related to the renovation of the Y. M. C. A. reading room, including drawings for a pair of doors and pine bookshelves to be made by C. Goodlow.
The miscellaneous folder includes a near print item 'From the "Abstract of the Enactments" published in 1859,' a list of subscriptions given in honor of Dwight Lyman Moody and for the funding of his visit to the University, and a printed invitation to the installation of E. A. Alderman as president of the University.
Contents List
- Topical
  - Y. M. C. A. materials 1878-1889, n.d.
  - J. H. Wheeler to F. P. Dunnington 1886 Sep 11
  - M. K. Johnston to F. P. Dunnington 1894 Sep 10
  - Printed Materials [18]90, 1895
  - F. P. Dunnington and William Fontaine to the University of Virginia Board of Visitors in reply to a letter from Maj. Jed. Hotchkiss 1895 Oct
  - Report of the committee on the Chapel 1895 May 27
  - Miscellaneous 1905, n.d.
  - Inserts from Syllabus of Industrial Chemistry Lectures ca. 1907-1928, n.d., (bound volume)
- Bound Volumes
  - Intermediate and senior math notes of F. P. Dunnington, University of Virginia 1867-1869
  - Syllabus of Industrial Chemistry Lectures by F. P. Dunnington n.d.